let questions = [
  {
    numb: 1,
    question: "Natural barriers of the immune system include all except which of the following?",
    answer: "Hair follicles",
    options: [
      "pH of secretions",
      "Coughing",
      "Hair follicles",
      "Intestinal bacteria"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 2,
    question: "The fundamental difference between primary and secondary organs of the lymphatic system is:",
    answer: "Maturation of lymphocytes occurs in primary organs, and activation occurs in secondary organs",
    options: [
      "Antibody production occurs only in the primary lymph organs",
      "Complement production occurs only in the primary lymph organs",
      "Maturation of lymphocytes occurs in secondary organs, and activation occurs in primary organs",
      "Maturation of lymphocytes occurs in primary organs, and activation occurs in secondary organs"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 3,
    question: "Toll-like receptors act in which way?",
    answer: "Enhance recognition of bacteria by phagocytic cells",
    options: [
      "Enhance recognition of bacteria by phagocytic cells",
      "Activate B cells to produce antibody",
      "Activate helper T cells",
      "Aid in processing antigen in the form of an MHC molecule"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 4,
    question: "Neutrophils and monocytes have receptors for which part of the immunoglobulin molecule?",
    answer: "Fc",
    options: [
      "Fc",
      "Fab",
      "Hinge region",
      "Variable region"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 5,
    question: "One B-cell marker of early-stage B-cell development is _____, whereas ____ is a marker for later stages of B-cell development.",
    answer: "CD10; CD20",
    options: [
      "CD20; CD10",
      "CD21; CD10",
      "CD10; CD20",
      "CD19; CD10"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "A double-positive T cell would express which markers?",
    answer: "CD4+CD8+CD3+",
    options: [
      "CD4+CD8+CD3+",
      "CD4CD8+CD3+",
      "CD4CD8CD3",
      "CD4+CD8-CD3+"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 7,
    question: "Which cell is considered to be a bridge between the innate and adaptive immune systems?",
    answer: "NK cell",
    options: [
      "NK cell",
      "Mast cell",
      "Monocyte-macrophage",
      "T cell"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 8,
    question: "_______ are involved in cell-mediated immunity, whereas _______ are involved in humoral immunity.",
    answer: "A and B",
    options: [
      "T cells; B cells",
      "T cells; antibodies",
      "B cells; T cells",
      "A and B"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 9,
    question: "Antigens that make very good immunogens include which of the following?",
    answer: "Proteins",
    options: [
      "Carbohydrates",
      "Proteins",
      "Both a and b",
      "Neither a or b"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 10,
    question: "The function of the complement system include(s) which of the following?",
    answer: "All of the above",
    options: [
      "Clearance of cellular debris",
      "Chemotaxis",
      "Lysis of bacteria",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 11,
    question: "When C3 is cleaved by C3 convertase, what is the result?",
    answer: "All of the above",
    options: [
      "C3a is released",
      "C3b is used as an opsonin",
      "C3b is combined with other complement proteins to form C5 convertase",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 12,
    question: "Characteristics of cytokines include which of the following?",
    answer: "All of the above",
    options: [
      "They can have a pleomorphic effect",
      "Cytokines are redundant",
      "Cytokines enhance cellular differentiation of lymphocytes",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 13,
    question: "Immunoglobulin idiotypes are antibodies with variations in the domains of which of the following?",
    answer: "VH and VL",
    options: [
      "CH1 and CH2",
      "VH and VL",
      "VH and CL",
      "CH1, CH2, and CH3"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 14,
    question: "Mannose-binding lectin is similar to which component of the classical pathway?",
    answer: "C1q",
    options: [
      "C3",
      "C2",
      "C1q",
      "C5a"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 15,
    question: "A patient with a viral infection to the ABC virus is found to have a high antibody titer to the ABC virus’s RNA, or anti-ABCr. Which of the following is true?",
    answer: "MHC class I molecules presented antigen to CD8+ T cells",
    options: [
      "MHC class I molecules presented antigen to CD4+ T cells",
      "MHC class II molecules presented antigen to CD8+ T cells",
      "MHC class I molecules presented antigen to CD8+ T cells",
      "MHC class II molecules presented antigen to CD4+ T cells"
    ]
  },


  //



    // Previous questions from 1 to 15
    {
      numb: 16,
      question: "What is the main difference between agglutination and precipitation reactions?",
      answer: "Agglutination occurs when the antigen is particulate",
      options: [
        "Agglutination occurs between a soluble antigen and antibody",
        "Agglutination occurs when the antigen is particulate",
        "Precipitation occurs when the antigen is particulate",
        "Precipitation occurs when both antigen and antibody are particulate"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 17,
      question: "Postzone causes false-negative reactions in antibody titers as a result of which of the following?",
      answer: "Excess antigen in test",
      options: [
        "Too much diluent added to test",
        "Excess antibody in test",
        "Excess antigen in test",
        "Incorrect diluent added to test"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 18,
      question: "Antibodies produced against two or more epitopes of specific antigen are considered ____________.",
      answer: "Polyclonal",
      options: [
        "Monoclonal",
        "Pleomorphic",
        "Dimorphic",
        "Polyclonal"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 19,
      question: "In the radial immunodiffusion test, the gel contains which of the following?",
      answer: "Antibody",
      options: [
        "The antigen to be tested",
        "Antibody",
        "Patient sample",
        "None of the above; the gel is the medium to which the antibody and antigen are applied in equal proportion"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 20,
      question: "Which statement is true regarding the radial immunodiffusion test?",
      answer: "The area of the precipitin ring is directly proportional to the concentration of antigen in the sample",
      options: [
        "The area of the precipitin ring is directly proportional to the concentration of antigen in the sample",
        "The area of the precipitin ring is directly proportional to the concentration of antibody in the sample",
        "The area of the precipitin ring is directly proportional to the concentration antibody and the antigen in the sample",
        "The area of the precipitin ring indicates a partial identity to the antibody in the sample"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 21,
      question: "The indirect antiglobulin test is for ______________, whereas the direct antiglobulin test is for __________.",
      answer: "Serum antibody; bound antibody",
      options: [
        "Serum antigen; bound antigen",
        "Serum antigen; bound antibody",
        "Serum antibody; bound antigen",
        "Serum antibody; bound antibody"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 22,
      question: "In an indirect immunofluorescent antibody test for CMV antibodies, the conjugated antibody used for visualizing is:",
      answer: "Antihuman globulin conjugated to a fluorescent dye",
      options: [
        "Antihuman globulin conjugated to a fluorescent dye",
        "Anti-CMV antibody conjugated to a fluorescent dye",
        "CMV virus conjugated to a fluorescent dye",
        "Antihuman globulin conjugated to an enzyme"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 23,
      question: "What is the difference between nephlometry and turbidimetry?",
      answer: "Nephlometry measures light scattered in a solution, and turbidimetry measures light transmitted through a solution",
      options: [
        "There is no difference between the two assays, only in name",
        "Nephlometry is a newer example of turbidimetry",
        "Nephlometry measures light transmitted through a solution, and turbidimetry measures light scattered in a solution",
        "Nephlometry measures light scattered in a solution, and turbidimetry measures light transmitted through a solution"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 24,
      question: "In an Ouchterlony immunodiffusion, the line of precipitation between the antibody and the antigen wells forms an X. This reaction would be described as which of the following?",
      answer: "Nonidentity",
      options: [
        "Nonidentity",
        "Partial identity",
        "Identity"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 25,
      question: "An initial titer of 4 followed by a subsequent titer of 16 for the same patient, drawn 2 weeks later, is indicative of which of the following?",
      answer: "Infection",
      options: [
        "Infection",
        "Convalescence",
        "Past exposure",
        "No exposure"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 26,
      question: "A deficiency of T cells can result in which of the following?",
      answer: "Fewer B cells maturing to plasma cells",
      options: [
        "Low levels of complement",
        "Dysfunctional macrophages",
        "Fewer B cells maturing to plasma cells",
        "Contact dermatitis"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 27,
      question: "A 2-week-old baby is seen for a possible infection with CMV. Which of the following statements is false?",
      answer: "An initial titer of anti-CMV IgG would need to be established",
      options: [
        "A positive anti-CMV result from baby’s specimen is inconclusive",
        "An initial titer of anti-CMV IgG would need to be established",
        "A positive result for anti-CMV IgM would indicate infection",
        "All are false statements"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 28,
      question: "What is the basic difference between the RPR and VDRL tests?",
      answer: "The RPR test is read macroscopically, whereas the VDRL is read microscopically",
      options: [
        "The RPR detects antigen, whereas the VDRL detects antibody",
        "The RPR test is read macroscopically, whereas the VDRL is read microscopically",
        "The RPR test is a treponemal test, whereas the VDRL is nontreponemal",
        "There is no difference because they are both specific test for syphilis"
      ]
    },

    //

  
      // Previous questions from 1 to 28
      {
        numb: 29,
        question: "A patient has the following hepatitis B serology: HBsAg: Negative, Anti-HBc: Positive, Anti-HBs: Positive. These results are consistent with which of the following?",
        answer: "Recovery from hepatitis B",
        options: [
          "Acute hepatitis B",
          "Chronic hepatitis B",
          "Recovery from hepatitis B",
          "Acute hepatitis A"
        ]
      },
      {
        numb: 30,
        question: "The HLA genes are inherited as:",
        answer: "Haplotypes: One haplotype from each parent",
        options: [
          "Diplotypes: Two diplotypes from each parent",
          "Haplotypes: One haplotype from each parent",
          "HLAs are not inherited, instead are proteins absorbed onto cells",
          "Only the HLA-A antigen is an inheritable trait"
        ]
      },
      {
        numb: 31,
        question: "Agglutination and precipitation that is visible depends on antigen–antibody ratios ________.",
        answer: "That are equivalent",
        options: [
          "With antigen in excess",
          "With antibody in excess",
          "That are equivalent",
          "All of the above"
        ]
      },
      {
        numb: 32,
        question: "Which of the following cell types is implicated in immediate hypersensitivity?",
        answer: "Mast cell",
        options: [
          "Neutrophil",
          "Mast cell",
          "Macrophage",
          "Monocyte"
        ]
      },
      {
        numb: 33,
        question: "Anti-dsDNA antibodies are associated with which of the following?",
        answer: "Systemic lupus erythematosus",
        options: [
          "Syphilis",
          "CMV infection",
          "Systemic lupus erythematosus",
          "Hemolytic anemia"
        ]
      },
      {
        numb: 34,
        question: "Rheumatoid factor is typically an IgM autoantibody with specificity for which of the following?",
        answer: "Fc portion of IgG",
        options: [
          "SS-B",
          "Double-stranded DNA",
          "Ribonucleoprotein",
          "Fc portion of IgG"
        ]
      },
      {
        numb: 35,
        question: "All of the following are autoimmune diseases except:",
        answer: "Rh disease of the fetus and newborn",
        options: [
          "Rheumatoid arthritis",
          "Rh disease of the fetus and newborn",
          "Grave’s disease",
          "Myasthenia gravis"
        ]
      },
      {
        numb: 36,
        question: "In Grave’s disease, one of the main autoantibodies is:",
        answer: "Antibody to TSHr",
        options: [
          "Anti-CCP",
          "Antibody to islet cells of pancreas",
          "Antibody to TSHr",
          "Anti dsDNA"
        ]
      },
      {
        numb: 37,
        question: "An autoantibody found in patients with which of the following?",
        answer: "Thyroglobulin",
        options: [
          "TSH receptor",
          "Islet cells",
          "CRP",
          "Thyroglobulin"
        ]
      },
      {
        numb: 38,
        question: "Skin testing for exposure to tuberculosis is an example of which type of hypersensitivity?",
        answer: "Type IV",
        options: [
          "Type I",
          "Type II",
          "Type III",
          "Type IV"
        ]
      },
      {
        numb: 39,
        question: "Which of the following is a test for specific treponemal antibody?",
        answer: "FTA-ABS",
        options: [
          "VDRL",
          "RPR",
          "FTA-ABS",
          "All of the above"
        ]
      },
      {
        numb: 40,
        question: "Serum tested positive for HBsAg and anti-HBc IgM. The patient most likely has which of the following?",
        answer: "Acute hepatitis B",
        options: [
          "Acute hepatitis C",
          "Chronic hepatitis B",
          "Acute hepatitis B",
          "Acute hepatitis A"
        ]
      },
      {
        numb: 41,
        question: "The main difference between leukemias and lymphomas is which of the following?",
        answer: "Leukemias are malignancies of cells in the bone marrow",
        options: [
          "Leukemias are malignancies of cells in the bone marrow",
          "Lymphomas are malignancies of cells in the bone marrow",
          "Lymphomas are classified as either acute or chronic",
          "Leukemias are malignancies in lymphoid tissue"
        ]
      },
      {
        numb: 42,
        question: "A 1-year-old boy is seen for having many recurrent infections with Streptococcus pneumoniae. Laboratory tests revealed a normal quantity of T cells, but no B cells and no immunoglobulins were seen on electrophoresis. Which of the following would most likely be the cause?",
        answer: "Bruton’s agammaglobulinemia",
        options: [
          "Chronic granulomatous disease",
          "Bruton’s agammaglobulinemia",
          "DiGeorge’s syndrome",
          "Wiskott-Aldrich syndrome"
        ]
      },
      {
        numb: 43,
        question: "A patient with hereditary angioedema has which of the following deficiencies?",
        answer: "C1 Inhibitor",
        options: [
          "C5-9",
          "Phagocytic cell function",
          "Mature B cells",
          "C1 Inhibitor"
        ]
      },

      //

 
        // Previous questions from 1 to 43
        {
          numb: 44,
          question: "A radiograph of a 1-year-old boy indicates the lack of a thymus. Complete blood count and flow cytometry confirm a below-normal lymphocyte count and a lack of T cells. Which of the following would most likely be the cause?",
          answer: "DiGeorge’s syndrome",
          options: [
            "DiGeorge’s syndrome",
            "Wiskott-Aldrich syndrome",
            "Bare lymphocyte syndrome",
            "Bruton’s agammaglobulinemia"
          ]
        },
        {
          numb: 45,
          question: "Severe combined immunodeficiency is characterized by which of the following?",
          answer: "All of the above",
          options: [
            "Diagnosed in infancy",
            "Shortened life span",
            "No antibody production",
            "All of the above"
          ]
        },
        {
          numb: 46,
          question: "A 3-year-old boy is seen by his physician because of many recent bacterial infections. Flow cytometry indicates normal levels of T and B cells. The nitroblue tetrazolium test for oxidative reduction is negative. The most likely cause is:",
          answer: "Chronic granulomatous disease",
          options: [
            "Wegener’s syndrome",
            "Chronic granulomatous disease",
            "Bruton’s agammaglobulinemia",
            "Diabetes mellitus"
          ]
        },
        {
          numb: 47,
          question: "A 25-year-old man was seen by his physician for recurrent infections. Immunoelectrophoresis revealed hypogammaglobulinemia. This man most likely has which of the following?",
          answer: "Common variable immunodeficiency",
          options: [
            "Bruton’s agammaglobulinemia",
            "Common variable immunodeficiency",
            "X-linked agammaglobulinemia",
            "DiGeorge’s syndrome"
          ]
        },
        {
          numb: 48,
          question: "In which disease would you expect to see an IgM spike on electrophoresis?",
          answer: "Waldenström’s macroglobulinemia",
          options: [
            "Transient hypogammaglobulinemia of infancy",
            "Wiskott-Aldrich syndrome",
            "Leukocyte adhesion disease",
            "Waldenström’s macroglobulinemia"
          ]
        },
        {
          numb: 49,
          question: "A person has an infected bug bite with pain, swelling, and redness. What is the cause of these physical symptoms of inflammation?",
          answer: "Increased blood flow and neutrophils to site",
          options: [
            "Production of antibody",
            "Secondary immune response",
            "Increased blood flow and neutrophils to site",
            "Activation of NK cells"
          ]
        },
        {
          numb: 50,
          question: "The type of graft rejection that occurs within minutes of a tissue transplant is ____________.",
          answer: "Hyperacute",
          options: [
            "Acute",
            "Chronic",
            "Hyperacute",
            "Accelerated"
          ]
        }
 
      
    
    

];
